

www.bhumilikalra.ca www.linkedin.com/in/bhumilikalra https://www.behance.net/bhumilikalra

A versatile and diligent design professional, with proven results driven experience in collaborative work environments. Knowledgeable in user experience and interface design, providing users with personalized cross-platform application experiences. Always pushing skills forward through self-education and personal projects.

Skills

· Adobe Illustrator

· Adobe After Effects

·HTML

· Adobe Photoshop

· Adobe Premiere Pro

· CSS/SASS

· Adobe XD

JavaScript

Project Experience

Filmate, UI and UX Designer

January 2021 - April 2021

Langara College, Vancouver, BC

Filmate is a multi-platform app that helps a group of up to 6 people to decide which movie to watch in a fun and non-compromising way.

What I did:

- Identified the user need and flow through survey data so that the user experience a seamless flow.
- Inhanced interactivity by designing graphics and screens following the 8-pixel design guidelines to give user interface a balanced look.
- Promoted the application by creating proposal, promotional videos and assets using Adobe suite which helped in reaching and presenting the application to targeted range of audience.

Results:

The project resulted to be audience favorite in the showcase event by Volition, Canada.

Savy, **UI and UX Designer**

September 2020 - December 2020

Langara College, Vancouver, BC

Savy is a data-driven web responsive platform to help people, communities and small businesses who want to learn about the process of recycling in Canada, by providing recycling information and visualizing data statistics of recycling waste.

What I did:

- Brainstormed and implemented innovative ideas for improving products and user experiences.
- Implemented design skills to create an interactive interface for recycling quiz. so that user can test their skills and explore more educational resources for recycling.
- Enhanced the possibility of user interaction by designing graphics and icons, insuring the data provided to the users is delivered in more engaging way.

Results:

The team achieved to present complete features in tight time span, solving a targeted users problem and even heard back from people who reached out to know more.

Langara College, Vancouver, BC

Buddy is an application connecting international students with the volunteers in Canada who are ready to help with on arrival challenges.

What I did:

- -Operated the team of designers and developers to create an MVP in tight time constraints by working remotely.
- -Build a marketing website by developing the WordPress theme for the project so that the details of the application could reach the wide range of audience.
- -Interpreted the survey results to created best user experience through user flow and wireframes providing undistorted information.

Results:

Strongly represented the unidentified need for the international student with a widely acceptable solution.

Volunteer Experience

Graphic Designer, DMM Langara

March 2020 - March 2021

DMM Langara is a club which aware students about digital marketing through workshops, seminars and industry meeting.

What I did:

- Designed the post for social media platform, Instagram and Facebook, keeping audience updated with the new content.
- Conserved the time of the team by designing reusable post templates.
- Followed the design plan and integrated the personal styling, making sure the design standards and branding are reflected in posts.

Provided support at Pink Skirt Day, Langara College

February 2020

Pink Shirt Day is an event organized annually to aware people about bullying and how to stop it. What I did:

- Decorated the event according to the team plans and structure.
- Motivated attendees to support the act of bullying in the society so that the count of awareness stay on hike.
- Encouraged involvement of people in awareness activities and raise funding.

Education

PDD in Web and Mobile Application Design and Development - January 2020 - April 2021

Langara College, Vancouver, BC

Certificate in Web Development - January 2019 - December 2019

ARC Educations, Ambala City, Haryana, India

Bachelor of Computer Application - September 2015 - April 2018

Chitkara University, Rajpura, Haryana, India

Awards